(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-26T01:34:06.294411",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
あ…
Ah...
緊張すっぎだなぁ…
I'm so nervous...
ああ…
Ah...
えむなんか… 帰りたい…
Um... I want to go home...
帰っていいすか？
Can I go home?
めちゃ、緊張する…あー…
I'm super nervous... ah...
え、でも楽しみではある…
But I am looking forward to it...
ね？ みんな楽しみにしてくれてるのかな？
Right? I wonder if everyone is looking forward to it.
ええ…でも… でもこれきついんだよな…
Um... but... but this is tough...
あーー！ つるっつる！ つるっつる！ ねえ！
Aahh! So slippery! So slippery! Hey!
いやばいこれっ！ 大好きすぎるっ！
This is crazy! I love you guys so much!
ちょっとみんなと会えるの楽しみなんだが…
I'm really looking forward to meeting everyone...
早く、早くうわ…
Hurry, hurry, whoa...
まだかな、まだかな… まだかな…
I wonder if it's time yet...
ああーー！ みんな！ どうもー！
Aah~! Everyone! Hello~!
うわ、失礼します！ 最初も最初、最初ちょっと失礼しますに…あ…
Whoa, excuse me! First things first, excuse me... ah...
どうも！ 沙花叉でーす！
Hello! It's Sakamata!
どうもどうもどうも！
Hello, hello, hello!
いやー、これ
Yeah, this...
なんの再現か分かる？
Do you know what this recreates?
分かる人分かるから！
If you know, you know!
で、ではちょっと
N-Now then...
おり、降りたいんですけど
I want to get down, but
あの降りる時ちょっと恥ずかしいから
it's a bit embarrassing to climb down...
あ、待ってだ。
Oh, wait.
あっち見えた！
Over there!
I see it!
あっち見えた！
Over there!
やだ！
No!
見ないだ！
Don't look!
みんな、どう？ステージが見えてるね
Everyone, how is it? You can see the stage, right?
バック、バック、バック、ナマーー！
Back, back, back, live!
秘密結社holoXの掃除屋でインターンのさかまたくろいどです！
I'm Sakamatacloidd, secret society holoX intern and cleaner!
どうも！いただきまーーす！
Hello! Bon appétit!
みんなちょっと心配したりしよう 今回は
Everyone might have been worried this time,
あれ？ちょっと音声入っちゃったんじゃないの？どうしようどうしようって思ったと思うんですけど
thinking, "Did audio get in? What do I do?"
今回は事故ではないです！
but this time it's not an accident!
ちゃんとね、あの音声さんも付いてくれてる演出でした！いえーい！
It was a production with the sound team properly supporting us! Yay!
いや、良かった良かった。本当にね、あのちょっと事故だと思われたら怖いなと思ったので
Phew, I'm so glad. I was really worried people might think it was an accident,
良かったといった感じで。
so I'm relieved.
あれ、なにこれ？何？これ？
Huh, what is this? What? This?
え、チップ？これチップじゃない？チップだよね？
Huh, a chip? Isn't this a chip? It's a chip, right?
やっと、なんか分かんないけどやったー！
Finally—I don't really get it, but yay!
チップもらった。あ、遅刻しなかったから起きれたかららしい。
I got a chip. Oh, apparently because I wasn't late and woke up on time.
え？なんかいじられてね？え？ひどくね？
Huh? Am I being teased? Huh? Isn't that harsh?
え、でも見て、かわいい！え、ちょっとわかんないけど嬉しい！やったー！じゃあちょっとしまっとこっかな、さかまた。
But look, it's cute! I don't really get it, but I'm happy! Yay! Let's put it away for now, Sakamata.
わ、チップしまうと言えば、ここ嬉しいよねって感じで、え、普通にしまいまーす。よいしょ。オッケーです！
When you say putting the chip away, I'm glad... so I'll just put it away. Heave-ho. Okay!
ね、どうどう？ドレスのさかまた、ね、可愛い？可愛い？どうどう？
Hey, how is it? Sakamata in a dress, hey, cute? Cute? How is it?
見て、可愛いしょ？
Look, isn't it cute?
わー！えっちな足首！きゃーー、見ないで！
Wow! Sexy ankles! Ahh, don't look!
可愛い、や、良かった良かった。なんとね、ま、さかまたくろいどももちろん可愛いんですが
Cute, phew, I'm so glad. And you know, Sakamatacloidd is of course cute, but
このステージ見てもいいんだよね？見てー！
you can look at this stage too, right? Look!
わーー！これ凄いんですよ！水族館ステージになってます！いえーい！
Whoa! This is amazing! It's turned into an aquarium stage! Yay!
なんかさ、あのリボンとかがさかまたのこのリボンと、おそろっちになったり
You know, the ribbons and things match Sakamata's ribbon and become matching,
あと、このシャツのね、噴水。ちょっとあの、シャツってこんな水入ったっけみたいな感じではあるんですが
and also the shirt's fountain. It's like, did shirts have water in them like this?
よく見たら怖いんですが、さかまたの分身があったりとか、あと、なんと！
If you look closely it's scary, but there are clones of Sakamata, and also, what's more!
新・一員さんたちが、3Dになっているとかどうとか。
The new members have become 3D or something.
うわーー！新・一員さんこわっ！えづる！めっちゃ怖い！けどな、
Whoaーー! The new members are scary! Creepy! Super scary! But you know,
これね、新・一員さんたちさかまたの仮面つけた仕様になってます！どうどう？新・一員さんたちも3D化しました！いえーい！
these new members have become customized wearing Sakamata's masks! How is it? The new members became 3D too! Yay!
え、あ、みんなたくさんの人が見に来てくれてるみたい、ありがとうございます！いえーい！え、あの、注文に、見に来てくれてるらしい！じ、じゃあちょっと、あ、ありがとうございます！みんなありがとー！
Oh, it looks like a lot of people came to see, thank you! Yay! Oh, um, they apparently came to see the order! Th-Then, um, ah, thank you! Everyone, thank you!
ではではでは、あのね、実はまだね、さかまたのステージにはたくさんのさかまた要素が隠されているので、探してみてくださーい！まだまだたくさんあるよ！
Now, actually, there are still many Sakamata elements hidden in Sakamata's stage, so please try looking for them! There are still lots of them!
ではでは、そろそろ気になってるんじゃない？どうですか？
Well then, aren't you getting curious? How is it?
さかまたちゃんのご、仮面、外してほしい？ねえねえ、外してほしい？ねえねえねえねえ、外してほしい？
Do you want me to take off Sakamata-chan's m-mask? Hey, hey, do you want me to take it off? Hey, hey, hey, hey, do you want me to take it off?
えー、外してみてもいいけど、うーん、どうなの？
Ugh, I could try taking it off, but hmm, how is it?
あ、そうだそうだ！あの、新・一員さんたち、なんか、湘南、大野里、湘南お魚な、さかまたの待期のときのアレをくれたら、さかまたにご褒美があるらしい！
Oh, that's right! Um, the new members, like, Shonan, Ono-sato, Shonan fish fish, if you give me that thing from Sakamata's waiting time, it seems there's a reward for Sakamata!
なので、ちょっとみんな
So, everyone...
しょ、お魚だ！
An—an actual fish!
流してください！
Send them in!
そのご褒美もろとろも
My rewards and everything...
ちょっと、やったあの子も
Wait, the one who did it too...
なんか、ーも思いましたけど。
I was thinking about that.
流して流して！どうぞ！
Send them in! Go ahead!
ねえ！違うでしょ！それじゃないでしょ！
Hey! That's not it! That's the wrong one!
ねえ！みんなのチャット見えてんだよ！
Hey, I can see everyone's chat, you know!
うふふふ！あー！やだー！
Ufufu! Ahh! No way!
なんか、来たんだけど！
Wait, more of them are coming!
なにこれ！やば！えっ！？
What is this?! No way, what?!
お魚？お魚だったよね？
Fish? Those were fish, right?
リアルすぎん？ちょっとリアルすぎ。
Too realistic! A bit too realistic!
みんなが、ねえ、みんながこれにすっからー！
Everyone—hey, everyone's gonna do this!
なにこれ！あー！いやー！きもちわるい！きも！
What is this?! Ahh! No! Gross! Creepy!
おい、坂又の3D初披露でしょが！なんだこれ！
Hey, this is Sakamata's 3D debut showcase! What is this?!
持てるの？これ。持てるよ、これ。きっしょ。きっしょ。
Can I hold this? I can hold this. Gross. Gross.
みんな、みんな、お魚の残骸よ。ほら、お披露目。
Everyone, look, a pile of fish carcasses. Tada!
これがみたかったんでしょ。ちゅっ、ちゅっ。む、ちゅんちゅんちゅんちゅん。
This is what you wanted to see, right? Mwah, mwah...
ねえ、何これ、きっしょ！気持ち悪いし！
Hey, what is this? Gross! And creepy!
勢いよすぎん？おら！勢いよすぎて！おら！
Isn't this too intense? Whoa! Too intense! Whoa!
何これ、きもい！でもね、みんな
What is this, creepy! But you know, everyone...
どう？どっちが可愛い？どう？坂又とこの魚、どっちが可愛い？
How is it? Which one is cuter? Between me and this fish, which is cuter?
もちろん、もちろん坂又だよね！そうだよね！
Of course, of course it's Sakamata! Right, exactly!
ああ、よかった、よかった。
Ah, good, good.
じゃ、ねえねえねえ、そうじゃもういいよ、いいよ、もうコメント！おいおい！大量にいるから！
Hey hey hey, okay that's enough, enough with the comments! Hey! There's a huge pile of them!
ねえ、処理落ちとかしたらどうすんの？これ！お仕置きしようか、これ！
Hey, what if the game lags from this?! Time for punishment!
やめてって言ってんの！おらおらおらおら！おらおらおらおら！
I told you to stop! Take that, take that!
よしよし。ふう。
There, there. Phew.
まあ、でも、これじゃ仮面は外せなーい。のー、のー、のー、みんな、存続にして、動けもいそう！
Well, even so, I can't take off my mask... no no no, everyone, let's keep it going, it's getting creepy!
残念、残念。
Too bad, too bad.
この動画を見てください
Please watch this video.
じゃ、このままやっていっちゃっか。
Well, shall we just keep going?
サプライズ？
A surprise?
いや、そうだよね、みんなお祝いしたいよね。坂又黒のすに配信だもんね。
Yeah, of course, everyone wants to celebrate. It's Sakamata's stream, right?
ええ、なんだろう、なんだろう？見てみよ、やめてみよ？
Eh, what could it be? Let's take a look!
仮面を外してください。
Please remove your mask.
いやいや！坂又黒が仮面を外すわけないじゃん！絶対外したりしないからね！
No way! There's no way I'd take off my mask! I'm definitely not taking it off!
いや、坂又さはんな、たかが、えっの、あー、か、仮面を脱いでしまった！うわあ！
Well, Sakamata-san, the mask came off! Whoa!
というわけで、えー坂又の3Dこんな感じとなってます。どう？可愛いでしょ？のの？
And that's what my 3D model looks like. How is it? Cute, right?
ガチ恋ちょ。
Hardcore simps...
可愛いんでしょ。
You think it's cute.
じゃあ早速ね、この水族館で遊んでいきたいと思います。あまいまーす！
Now then, let's play around in this aquarium. Yay!
じゃあ、まずは何してほしい、坂又に？
First of all, what do you want me to do?
ねえ、みんな何してほしいの？
Hey everyone, what do you want me to do?
ちょっとみんなのコメント見て、拾ってちょこな。
Let's check everyone's comments and pick some.
何してほしい？何してほしい？
What do you want? What do you want me to do?
投げい、投げい？
Nagei, nagei?
みんな可愛いしか言ってないじゃん！
Everyone's just saying "cute"!
ねえ、何してほしいか言ってよ！言って！
Hey, tell me what you want me to do! Say it!
ジャンプ？え？
Jump? Eh?
ジャンプ、ジャンプ、ジャンプ、ジャンプ。と？
Jump, jump, jump, jump. And?
坂又がね、一番エッチだと思う飛び方しようか。これぐらい。
Let's do the sexiest jump possible. About this high.
これ、これぐらい。これぐらいが一番エッチだと思いませんか？
This high. Don't you think this is the sexiest?
怒られるわ、また。やれよ、大人たちの冷たいタイミングが来る。
I'll get scolded again. Here come the adults with their cold timing.
まね、とりあえずは、このね、3Dの素晴らしいボディを手に入れたからにはね、坂又のフィジカルのお手目ってやつを
Anyway, now that I've acquired this amazing 3D body, I should show off my physical prowess...
皆さんに見せてあげようかなと。
I thought I'd show it to everyone.
甘い……。
Too easy...
じゃあ行きますか。
Well, shall we go?
せーの、どん！
Ready, set, go!
沙花叉スポーツ！イェーイ！
Sakamata Sports! Yay!
寿司ゾンビｗ
Sushi zombie lol
はい、えー沙花叉スポーツです。
Yep, um, it's Sakamata Sports.
まあね、沙花叉黒衣、最近ね、配信できたりとか腹筋もありますし、余裕あるんじゃないのかななんて思っちゃったりするんですよね。
Well, you know, Sakamata Chloe has been able to stream recently and has abs, so I thought maybe I have some room to spare.
じゃあまずね、定番の、反復横跳びと、半身横跳び……反復横跳びね！はい。スポーツテスト的なことだよね。
So first, the standard side-to-side jumps, half-body side-to-side jumps—side-to-side jumps! Yeah. It's like a sports test.
たぶんスポーツテストはやりたいと、思います！
I think I want to do the sports test!
なんか、しゅっしゅって見たら動きでしょ？いや、できるよ沙花叉。
You know, if you look at "shu shu", that's movement, right? No, Chloe can do it.
だって、ダンスレッスンもしてたし、うん、絶対できるから。任せてください。
Because I've been doing dance lessons too, yeah, I can definitely do it. Leave it to me.
行きますかっ。
Shall we go?
何秒？
How many seconds?
20秒？
20 seconds?
いや余裕だよ。おっ、準備はやっ。
Nah, I've got this. Oh, prep is fast.
準備えっぐ。
Prep is crazy fast.
行きますよ！
Here we go!
はい！
One!
２！
Two!
３！
Three!
４！
Four!
５！
Five!
６！
Six!
７！
Seven!
８！
Eight!
９！
Nine!
１０！
Ten!
１１！
Eleven!
１１回！イェーイ！
11 times! Yay!
やば、沙花叉の、沙花叉のね、え、なんか
Man, Sakamata's, Sakamata's, um, like
お、髪の声が、え、動き方が変だとか、線10本ぐらいないと、失礼じゃん！どう考えても！
Oh, my hair's voice, um, her movement is weird, or if there aren't about 10 lines, that's rude! No matter how you think about it!
ちゃんと頑張ってたりしょうが、え、でもさ反復横跳びってこんなもんだよね？
Even if I worked hard, um, but side-to-side jumps are normally like this, right?
え、ちがう？俺の知ってる反復横跳びって違った？え、外し方も間違ってた？え？
Huh, is it different? Was the side-to-side jump I know different? Huh? Was the way I took it off wrong too? Huh?
なんで？嘘だ！ずっとやってた。え、本当違うんですか？え？
Why? No way! I've been doing it the whole time. Huh, is it really different? Huh?
すみませんでした。
I am so sorry.
あの、で、でも、でも、あの、大体OKです。止めてましたから。
Um, but, but, but, um, roughly it's fine. I stopped it.
やってやった！おっ、えーートレンド１位なんだって、今！
I did it! Oh, it's trending #1 right now!
みんなありがとう！もっともっとシャープに、えっとこういった、沙花叉黒衣、スリーニーで呟いてくれると嬉しいなって思います！よろしくお願いします！
Thank you everyone! I'd be happy if you tweeted more sharply about Sakamata Chloe with three knees! Please look forward to it!
はあ、まあでもね、運動できたもんだと思うけど、ま、でもコート着てるからな。
Haah, well, I guess I managed to exercise, but well, I'm wearing a coat after all.
これ３００キロあるしな。重いよね、やっぱ。
This is 300kg too. It's heavy, after all.
しかも暑い。やっぱね、もう運動したから。
Plus it's hot. Well, you know, since I already exercised.
あちあちだ。もうこれはしょうがないな。あちちだからかな。
It's super hot. Well, this can't be helped. Probably because it's hot.
この動画を見てください。
Please watch this video.
いや、もう騙されないよ！沙花叉黒衣は、そのね、動画を見たら絶対に、なんか、悪い大人たちが何かを考えているっていうことでしょう。
No, I won't be fooled anymore! Sakamata Chloe, if you watch that video, definitely, like, bad adults are plotting something.
その動画なんて絶対、沙花叉黒衣は観ないからね！わかっ
That kind of video, Sakamata Chloe will definitely never watch! I underst—
速いよ！準備が、準備が速いよ！
So fast! The prep is, the prep is so fast!
ねえ！よくない準備！絶対違うよね？ねえ、もういいって！もう観たよ！ねえ、どういうこと？
Hey! Bad preparation! That's definitely wrong, right? Hey, enough already! I already saw it! Hey, what is this?
ああ、もう大激変で、おかしなる！あーー！
Ah, it's a huge upheaval, I'm going crazy! Aahh!
でも今回は特に、もう何もできないはずなんだけどな。
But this time especially, I shouldn't be able to do anything anymore.
コートを脱いでください。
[Text: Please take off your coat]
いやいやいや、暑いとは言ったけど、コートは脱がないですから沙花叉。脱ぎそうで脱がない女っていうのが沙花叉黒衣ですから、絶対脱いだりしませんから。わかりました？
No no no, I said it was hot, but Sakamata doesn't take off her coat. A woman who looks like she'll take it off but doesn't is Sakamata Chloe, so I will definitely never take it off. Understand?
聞いてる？みんな聞いて……。
Are you listening? Everyone, listen...
わっ！わあ！脱いじゃったーー！
Whoa! Wah! I took it off—!
２回目ないよ。ね？電動ないんや。
There's no second time. Right? No motorized stuff.
ってことで、ありがとうございます。え、これいいのかな？
And with that, thank you very much. Um, is this okay?
え、いいんだよね？一応、おっけー。
Um, it's fine, right? Basically, okay.
え、これ大丈夫？本当？
Um, is this okay? Really?
え、でもいいんだよね？いいって言われたから、いいんだよね？
Um, but it's fine, right? Since I was told it's fine, it's fine, right?
え、かわいいでしょ？どうなの？
Um, cute right? How is it?
やっぱね、コートなしもエッチだななんて。
As expected, without the coat is also pretty lewd.
うわあ！
Whoa!
ちょっとあんまり見ちゃだめ。だめ。
Don't look too much. No.
というわけで、次の種目、どん！
And with that, the next event, boom!
沙花叉ショー
[Title: Sakamata Show]
状態そらし。えー
Back extension. Um...
えー、沙花叉クロヱの 状態らしい。
Eh, Sakamata Chloe's... physical condition or something.
やったこと、まあ、でも、あ、あるっちゃある。あるっちゃあるけど、うん。
I've done it before, well, I mean, yeah, kind of. Kind of, yeah, but um.
何センチぐらいが基本なんですかね？何センチぐらい？
What's the standard number of centimeters, I wonder? How many centimeters?
あ、めじゃー、めじゃーが落ちる。あー！
Ah, a measuring tape, the tape measure fell. Ah—!
えーと、あ、でも、でも、でも、え、多分なんだけど、
Um, but, but, but, um, probably,
60とか65？
60 or 65?
50、60、60？くらい？現状、だえ？
50, 60, 60? Around there? Currently, what?
60とか無理かな？いけそうじゃない？頑張れば。
Is 60 impossible? Don't you think I can do it if I try hard?
ちょっとやってみる。やってみるか、せっかくだし。行きますか。
Let's try it. Let's give it a try since we're at it. Shall we go?
沙花叉クロヱちゃんの 状態らしい。
Sakamata Chloe's physical condition, apparently.
いやさ、あの、企画とは言えかわいそうだよね、床で寝そべって。
I mean, though it's just a segment, it's kinda pitiful, lying down on the floor.
そう思わない？みんな。行くよー。
Don't you think so, everyone? Here we go.
みんな、いい？行くよー。沙花叉の「にー」のタイミングで行くからね。せーの、ふっ！
Everyone, ready? Here we go. We'll go on Sakamata's "two" timing, okay? Ready, and— hup!
あー、どう、どう、どう？何センチですか？何センチ？何センチ？どう、どう？
Ah, how is it, how is it, how is it? How many centimeters? How many centimeters? How many centimeters? How is it, how is it?
え、何みんな？スポーツやるわけ？ねぇ、ねぇ、どう、どう、何センチ？何センチ？
Huh, why is everyone doing sports? Hey, hey, how is it, how is it, how many centimeters? How many centimeters?
おれが勝ってんじゃね？ねぇ、何センチ？何センチ？
Aren't I winning? Hey, how many centimeters? How many centimeters?
何センチ、何センチ出して、きんち、早く！
How many centimeters, show me how many centimeters, hurry up!
どう、どう、どう、どう？もう無理！
How is it, how is it, how is it, how is it? I can't take it anymore!
おっさん、みんな死んだ？
Old men, did everyone die?
何センチでした？え、15センチ？
How many centimeters was it? Eh, 15 centimeters?
ねぇ！絶対そんなことない！
Hey! There's no way that's true!
いや、でもずっとそんなことないの？え、いままった上がってたよね？え？
No, but haven't I always been like that? Eh, my torso was going up, right? Eh?
もう回リフレジ、あ、え、もう回、そう、されるんだっけ？もう回？え、え？
Once more refresh, ah, eh, once more, yeah, was it supposed to be done again? Once more? Eh, eh?
台本、台本にないじゃん？え？
It's not in the script? Eh?
うそか？い、あ、いい仕様じゃ。しょうがないな。もう回ね？
Is that a lie? Well, ah, it's a good feature then. Can't be helped. Once more, okay?
行くよ。え、ちょっとさ、メジャーもちゃんとして？行くよ。
Here we go. Hey, wait, make sure the tape measure is proper too. Here we go.
せーの、ふっ！あ、どう、どう、どう？
Ready, and— hup! Ah, how is it, how is it, how is it?
めっちゃ上がってる、めっちゃ上がってる！ねぇ！
It's going up a lot, it's going up a lot! Hey!
どうですか？ねぇ、何センチは？今で今、お前今測って？測って！
How is it? Hey, what about the centimeters? Measure right now! Measure!
な、何センチ、何センチだって、聞いて、早く！
Wh— how many centimeters, how many centimeters, listen, hurry up!
もう無理！何センチ？何センチだけ嫌なら！
I can't do this anymore! How many centimeters? If you hate centimeters!
何センチだけ嫌なら、絶対いやだ、絶対いやだ！
If you hate just centimeters, I definitely hate that, definitely hate that!
次次行きましょうかじゃないでしょ。ねぇ？次行きましょうかじゃないでしょ。
You shouldn't say "Shall we move on to the next one?" right? Hey? You shouldn't say "Shall we move on?"
えろい。頑張ったのに。
Lewd. Even though I worked hard.
ということで、最後さ、そう。
And so, finally, yeah.
沙花叉クロヱの自信がある、お待たせね。腹筋です。
Sakamata Chloe's confident field, sorry to keep you waiting. Abdominal muscles.
いやもう、これはね、普段からやってますんで。
Well, I mean, I do this regularly, so.
じゃ、行きますか。
Shall we go go then?
なんこれ？え、なんか、腹筋ローラじゃない、これ？
What is this? Eh, isn't this an ab roller?
腹筋ローラですよね、これね。え？
It's an ab roller, isn't it? Eh?
いや、腹筋でしょ、やるの。
No, abs are what we're doing.
え、腹筋ローラやるんですか？地獄なの？
Eh, are we doing ab roller? Is this hell?
え、地獄じゃない？え、沙花叉これじゃない？やるの。
Eh, isn't this hell? Eh, isn't this what Sakamata is doing?
かわいそうじゃない？え？
Isn't it pitiful? Eh?
え、お願いします、よろしくですじゃない、レイ、やばい、やばい、やばい、しぬしぬしぬ！
Eh, please, it's not "yoroshiku desu", wait, yaba, yaba, yaba, dying dying dying!
しぬ！あー！
Dying! Ah—!
これがお望みか？な！これでいいのか大人たちは！
Is this what you wished for? Ha! Are the adults happy with this?!
よくないよね、マネちゃん。マネちゃんグッドサイン出してるんだけど。
It's not good, right, Mane-chan? Mane-chan is giving a thumbs-up sign though.
え、なに、こいつのルール？ねえ、もう。かわいそうさが、
Eh, what, what's her rule? Hey, seriously. The pitifulness,
え、なんか普通の腹筋だったら自信あるんですか？って言われたんですけど。
Eh, someone asked, "Are you confident if it's regular sit-ups?"
はい！超自信あります。今やってるから。
Yes! I'm super confident. Because I'm doing it right now.
え、30秒で何回いける？え、そりゃもう、40秒いけんじゃね？
Eh, how many times can I do it in 30 seconds? Eh, surely I can do around 40, right?
いや、40秒いけるっしょ！いいですよ。あ、やっていって。じゃあ40秒いきましょうか。
No, 40 seconds is totally doable! Sure. Ah, go ahead. Then shall we go for 40 seconds?
ちょっとや、やりましょう。ベッド、どうする？
Let's do it. Bed, what should I do?
え、はい、こう？こうで、こう？え？
Eh, yes, like this? Like this, like this? Eh?
違う？え？違うの？あ、あれ？大人たちが困ってる。
Wrong? Eh? Wrong? Oh, huh? The adults are troubled.
あ、こっち？あ、こっちか。あ、わかった。
Ah, this way? Ah, this way. Ah, I get it.
なんか変なの？
Is something weird?
行くよ、いい？
Here we go, ready?
いてっ！
Ouch!
にええええ
No way...
腹筋崩壊の生活ちょっと辛いんだけどさ
Living a "core-destroying" life is kind of tough...
ううう
Ugh...
くうっ！ちょっ…
Ngh! Hold on...
ほう、くっ！
Hah, ugh!
な、の…
Wh- What...
あーっ！
Ahh!
ぎゅう…ううっ！
Tight... ugh!
どう？
How is it?
な、え？十回？
Wh- What? Ten times?
え？なんかどういうことですかって怒られてるんだけど。
Eh? People are getting mad asking what I mean.
そんな、だってさ腹筋崩壊するって聞いてなかったよね、坂本ね？
I mean, nobody told me my abs would get destroyed, right, Sakamoto?
まねちゃんも今後合流しちゃうんだから、なんかさー、ねえ！
Mane-chan is gonna join in later too, so come on, hey!
くみ、まね、まね、まねーっ！
Wait, Mane, Mane, Maneee!
うるさい、うるさい、うるさい！
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
だってさ、疲れてるよね、今考えても。お家だよ？ねえ、こんな。
I mean, I'm exhausted, right? Even thinking about it, I'm at home!
ねえ、キモいんだって、そんで。ペイズリーがヤバいって。
Hey, it's gross, and paisley is crazy.
こんなにね、疲れちゃったんですけど、ま、じゃあ次に移りたいと思います。
I'm so exhausted, but well, let's move on to the next thing.
ひどいよね。はい、次！
That's awful. Okay, next!
沙花叉ショー
[Sakamata Show]
まあね、水族館だから、沙花叉のシャチのショーを見せてあげたいと思います。
Well, since it's an aquarium, I'd like to show you Sakamata's killer whale show.
そしてこちらを使います。
And we will use this.
おっ、わあ！スイカ！
Oh, wow! A watermelon!
ははは、ごま、腕力やばすぎ。こちらのスイカを使って
Haha, Goma, your arm strength is insane. Using this watermelon...
えー、ヘディングをしたいとと思います。連続で7回？
Uh, I'd like to do heading. Seven times in a row?
7回、7回できれば坂本人の勝ちね。行くよ？
Seven times, if I can do it seven times, Sakamoto wins. Ready?
行きます！
Here I go!
まねちゃんが持ってんだよ、いま。まねちゃんがフェイントしようとしてる、ねえ！
Mane-chan is holding it right now. Mane-chan is trying to fake me out, hey!
はやっ…はい！
So fast... Okay!
はい！よいしょに。
Yes! Heave-ho.
よーし、で、なんかさ持ってる挙動と投げる場所が違うんだけど。
Alright, but somehow the holding movement and where it's thrown are different.
6回！ばん！
6 times! Bam!
ねぇ、一回さ、なんかさ投げ方さ、完全に落す気まんまん…ねぇ！
Hey, the way you throw it looks like you completely intend to drop it... hey!
え、クリア？やった！
Eh, cleared? Yay!
チップだ、やったー！
Chips, yay!
チップ貰った見てみて！よかった。ちゃんと勝った、賭けに勝ったね。やったー！チップ嬉しい！
Look, I got chips! Yay! I won the bet fair and square. Woohoo! I love chips!
ありがとうございます。肝心の中身はちょっと嬉しくなっちゃう。しかもいっぱいあるわ。
Thank you so much. The actual contents make me a bit happy. Plus there's so many.
やったー！疲れた。もう終わりですか？
Yay! I'm tired. Is it over already?
じゃあ、次の沙花叉ショーは、えー、スイカを頭の上のバランスを取りたいと思います。
Well then, for the next Sakamata Show, um, I'd like to balance a watermelon on my head.
10秒間、魚、魚じゃなくて
For 10 seconds, a fish, not a fish...
スイカ、10秒間スイカを頭の上でバランス取りたいと思います。
watermelon, I want to balance a watermelon on my head for 10 seconds.
あーっ、逆！違う！遊ばないで、坂本って！やめて！
Ah, reverse! No! Don't mess around, Sakamoto! Stop it!
行くよ？行きますよ？
Ready? Here we go?
よし、行けたかな？やったー！優勝！
Alright, did I make it? Yay! Champion!
よかった。無事ね、沙花叉ショーもできましたね。
Phew. Thankfully, the Sakamata Show was a success.
おっ！チップボール！やったー！見てみて！
Oh! Chip ball! Yay! Look, look!
ロト？食べます。
Lotto? I'll eat it.
タブッチみたい。んー！で、これチップ貰いに行く？よし、締めますね。
Like Tabutti. Mmm! So, should I go get these chips? Okay, I'll wrap it up.
あ、よかった。入れました。ちょっとね、摩擦で痛かったかなって思うんですけど、よかったー！
Ah, great, it went in. It hurt a bit from friction, I guess, but yay!
ということで、最後の…
And with that, the final...
最後のコーナーに突入したいと思います。
I'd like to dive into the final corner.
最後のコーナーは！沙花叉ボーナスイエーイ！
The final corner is! Sakamata Bonus! Yay!
このコーナーはなんと！沙花叉が可愛いポーズをすればするほど、ご褒美がもらえるそうです！
In this corner, apparently, the cuter poses Sakamata strikes, the more rewards I'll get!
最高！
Awesome!
ってことで可愛いポーズ、可愛いポーズか、うーん、難しいな。
So cute poses... cute poses... hmm, that's hard.
じゃあ、ちょっと行きますね。
Well then, let's go.
じゃ、セクシーポーズ？あはん。ふふふふっ。
Now, a sexy pose? Ahun. Hehe.
どう？可愛いかった？どう？可愛い？なになになの？可愛い？
How was it? Was it cute? How's that? Cute? What's going on? Is it cute?
ねえ、みんな、ねえ、どっち？それブーイングなの？喜んでるの？どっち？
Hey, everyone, hey, which is it? Are you booing? Are you cheering? Which one?
ねえ、どっちなの？わかんないんだよ、それ。可愛い、あ、でも可愛いって
Hey, which is it? I don't get it. Cute—ah, but if you say "cute"
みんなが可愛いって言ってくれるなら、可愛いか、ほんなら。ん、可愛いか。
if everyone says it's cute, then I guess it is. Hmm, is it cute?
え、みんなはさ、どんなポーズしてほしい？ねえ、マレーちゃん、マレーちゃんが
Hey, what kind of poses do you guys want me to do? Hey, Maley-chan, Maley-chan—
すっげえさ、なんか疑問そうな顔で、ま、可愛い？みたいな感じで買ってきたんだけど。
has this super questioning look like, "Well, is that cute?"
え、ちょっとみんなどんなポーズしてほしい？沙花叉がみんなが言ってくれるポーズしよっかなって思うんだけど。
Hey, what kind of poses do you all want? I was thinking of doing whatever poses you guys suggest.
だんだんバージョンしてほしいの、沙花叉に。
I want you to give me more versions, Sakamata.
ちょっとやっちゃおうかな、沙花叉狂いちゃん。
Shall I do it a bit, Sakamata-crazy-chan?
いやでも、顔が可愛いから、何にしても可愛いからな、たぶん。わかんない。
But hey, since my face is cute, whatever I do will probably be cute. I don't know.
あいじバランス、何あいじバランスって？ふう。
I-balance? What's I-balance? Whew.
なんか、え、すごい笑われてんだけど、今。え？ファィティングポーズいいよ。
Wait, I'm being laughed at a lot right now. Huh? A fighting pose is good.
らっ！ふふふっ。
Raa! Haha.
Yバランス？で、これ？え、なんか大人の笑ってんだけど。え？違うの？
Y-balance? So like this? Huh, adults are laughing. Huh? Is that wrong?
え、ちょっと分かんないかも。ごめん。え、どういうこと？ってことで、ちょっと教えていただけると幸いです。
Uh, I might not get it. Sorry. What do you mean? So, I'd appreciate it if you could teach me.
あ、チップ？え？チップ来た！え、いいんだ！
Oh, chips? Huh? Chips came! Oh, really!
え、なんか面白かったからチップくれたんだ。それってさ、可愛いと思って当たったんですかね、こっちは。やった！３枚ももらえた！
Oh, you gave me chips because it was funny? Did you think that was cute when you hit it? Yay! I got three of them!
まあ、習ってよかったか。
Well, I'm glad I learned it.
あと、あと、スクワット？バカ、バカ言うんじゃねえ。
And then... squat? Idiot, don't say stupid things.
行くよ！
Here I go!
ちょっと未来で、ちょっと未来で。ちょっとマズかったかな。
A bit in the future, a bit in the future. Was that a bit bad?
ちょっとあのスクワットは、やめよっか。ね？
Let's drop that squat thing. Okay?
え、なんかさ、みんなさ、可愛いポーズって言ってんのにさ、沙花叉で遊ぼうとしてるよね？違うよね、絶対にね、やること。今やるべきことじゃないよね？
Hey, everyone, you keep saying "cute pose," but you're trying to mess with Sakamata, right? That's wrong. That's definitely not what we should be doing right now, is it?
なんか可愛いのないの？ねえ！可愛いポーズをプリーズなんだけど、ずっと言ってんだけど！ねえ！
Don't you have anything cute? Hey! I've been saying "cute pose, please" the whole time! Hey!
顔が可愛いから何やっても可愛いってことかな？。ちゅった？なんだろしょんなんか。
Is it because my face is cute, so whatever I do is cute? Did you say that? What is that?
顔のポーズ？あ、いいよ。顔。がおがおがおがお。がお？
A facial pose? Ah, okay. Face. Grr grr grr grr. Grr?
お！めっちゃチップ来た！え, よかった！
Oh! So many chips came! Oh, great!
え、なんで、なんで？え、めっちゃ、何、何枚これ？うわ、すごいっぱる5枚！
Huh, why, why? Wait, how many are there? Wow, that's five!
え、ありがとうございます。たくさんのチップ。やっぱチップ最強。
Thank you very much. Lots of chips. Chips are definitely the best.
なん台？ちょっとさ、ふざけっぽりし。じょうじゅなっち。
How many? Come on, joking around.
どうだい？ずず立ち。できる。
How's that? Standing on tiptoe. I can do it.
できてる、これ。どう？
Am I doing it? How is it?
なってる、なってる？難しいんだけど。え、こうか？こう、あ、こうじゃない？
Is it right? It's hard. Wait, like this? Like this—ah, is this it?
オッケー、オッケー！え、これ可愛い？
Okay, okay! Huh, is this cute?
みんな正気か？可愛くないよな？可愛くはないよな、少なくともな。
Are you guys in your right minds? It's not cute, right? It's not cute, at least.
え、あと何がいい？ブリッジ。
Uh, what else do you want? A bridge.
あー、いいよ。やろうか、一応。いやいや、みんながそんな、あれこれ言うんなら、やってやりますよと。
Ah, fine. I'll do it, just in case. No, no, if everyone's saying all that, I'll go ahead and do it.
見てるね？行くよ。
You're watching, right? Here I go.
ねぇ、ブリッジ、ブリッジって感じでね、ね
Like, bridge, bridge, you know?
よかった。
Good.
次行こうかな。
Shall we go next?
あとは、あとは？
What else, what else?
あとなんかさ、え、上がってない？え？みんな？
Also, like, wait, didn't it go up? Eh? Everyone?
え、大丈夫？あ、ちょっとカメラさんしっかりしてもらえるかな？ねえねえねえねえ。
Eh, are you okay? Ah, camera person, can you steady yourself? Hey hey hey hey.
どう考えてもさ、できてたよね、今の。撮り方は悪くないんじゃない？
No matter how you look at it, you pulled it off, right? Wasn't that a decent way to shoot?
ごめん！ごめん！声大きすぎ？いやぁな。あ、で、ちょっとマリン先輩のポーズにしようかな？
Sorry! Sorry! Was my voice too loud? Haha. Ah, so, maybe I'll do Marine-senpai's pose?
よ。どう？どう？セクシー？どうどうどう？どうですか？
Yo. How is it? How is it? Sexy? How is it, how is it? How is it?
ははは。
Haha.
これ、これでいいのか？本当に。
Is this... is this really okay?
体育座り、あぁ、ぺたん座り。
Gym sitting, ah, flat sitting.
いいよ。体育座りはさっきやった、やったっちゅーか、やった、やった、やったけど、何口が？
Okay. Gym sitting was what I did earlier, or rather, I did it, did it, did it, but wait, my mouth?
どう？どうですか？どうですか？
How is it? How is it? How is it?
な？次、この次ぐらいにラストにしようかな？
Right? Shall we make the next one about the last one?
どう？
How?
はい？
Okay?
じゃあ、最後のおにしようかな？
Well then, shall we make it the last one?
何にしようかな？
What should we make it?
よし、じゃあ、最後のなにしようかな？
Alright, well then, what should I make the last one?
なににしようかな？
What should I make it?
よし。
Alright.
死ぬんだ、ここで。
I'm gonna die here.
あとは？
What else?
ね、なんかさ、あの、しゃがみ座りっ て比較的坂本に優し いって いう噂聞いたけど、みんな大丈夫？
Hey, you know, I heard a rumor that crouching is relatively kind to Sakamata, but is everyone okay?
大丈夫かな？
Will you be okay?
ダッチュのポーズ？ダッチュのポーズってあれ？こういうやつ？じゃ、いくよ？
The "Dacchu" pose? What's the "Dacchu" pose? This kind of thing? Well, here we go?
ダッチュの？
The "Dacchu's"?
な？どうだ？どうだ？どうだ？オッケー？
Right? How is it? How is it? How is it? Okay?
よかった？
Was it good?
やったー！よかった！
Yay! That's great!
え！めっちゃ多い！え！
Eh! So many! Eh!
やばー！めっちゃもらった！見て！
No way! I got so many! Look!
すごい！めちゃくちゃいっぱいもらった！え、え、え、え、これ、これ、これ、いっぱい欲しいが、あった！
Amazing! I got so, so many! Eh, eh, eh, eh, I really wanted lots of these, and there were!
これ、これ、これ、いっぱい星出たわ！
This, this, this, lots of stars came out!
これ、これ、これ、これこれこれ。そうそうそう、これこれこれ。
This, this, this, this, this, this. That's right, this, this, this.
しまっときます。大事に奥の方にし まっときます。
I'll put it away. I'll store it carefully in the back.
やったー！よかったよかった！
Yay! I'm so glad!
じゃあ、坂本黒ね、こんなにね、可愛かった坂本黒ちゃんのボーナスステージも おしまいですが、
Well then, Sakamata Chloe's, such cute Sakamata Chloe-chan's bonus stage is coming to an end,
実は、ステージ、ここだけじゃ
Actually, the stage isn't just here...
ないんです。
It's not.
おー、みんなどんなステージだと思う？どんなだと思う？優しさみて、みんなのコメント見るわ。
Ooh, what kind of stage do you guys think it is? What do you think? Show some kindness, let's see everyone's comments.
どんなだと思う？
What do you think?
なんかみんな、みんなの反応可愛いな。
Somehow everyone's reactions are so cute.
うん。
Yeah.
おおー！あ、でも、え？
Ooh! Ah, but, eh?
みんなの推理、いい感じだよ。それかなりいい感じ。近いよライブ。
Everyone's deductions are pretty good. That's pretty good. The live is close.
風呂？
A bath?
ねえ、誰が3Dでお風呂に入るんだよって！ねえ。普段から入んないのに風呂入るわけないだろ、3Dなんだから。
Hey, who takes a bath in 3D?! Hey. I don't even take baths normally, no way I'd take one in 3D.
じゃあ、次のステージに 移りたいと 思います！
Well then, I'd like to move on to the next stage!
移動、レッツ、ゴー！呼びます！お呼びになりまーす！
Moving, let's go! Calling! Now being called!
おさかなだー、なんか食べよっかな、どれに食べよっかな
It's a fish, I wonder what I should eat, which one should I eat?
助けて！助けて！殺される！やったー！大好きって、
Help! Help! I'm gonna get killed! Yay! "I love you,"
さかもとなかま、なかま、フレンド、フレンド、フレンドだよ、わかる？フレンド、オッケー？フレンド。
Sakamata, companions, companions, friend, friend, friend, you know? Friend, okay? Friend.
助けて！助けて！助けて！誰が？だれが好きって？
Help! Help! Help! Who? Who do you love?
じゃあ、ここどこにしようか、みんな！
Well then, where should we make this place, everyone?
さっきね、おちちくれてる子もいたんですけど、
Earlier, some people were offering milk, but...
な、なんと！カジノでーす！
W-What, it's a casino!
やったー！カジノ取ったんだよ！すごくない？
Yay! I got a casino! Isn't that amazing?
いや、マジで、うめさんたち本当にありがとうございました！ロマン、ロマンをたくさんありがとうございました！といった感じでね、
Seriously, Ume-san and everyone, thank you so much! Thank you so much for so much romance! With that said,
あのね、ここめちゃくちゃいろいろね、ロマンが溢れた設備が
You know, here, there are so many facilities overflowing with romance...
始まるよ！
It's starting!
見てほしいなー
I want you to see it,
くるって
spinning around.
みためた？
Did you see it?
お、見て！このカジノにありそうなLED変えてないのかっていう電飾でポチポチしてるやつ！
Look at those blinking LEDs that look like they've never been replaced in this casino!
めっちゃいいよね、これね。
It's so good, isn't it?
そして！うわあ、見て！
And! Wow, look!
すごーい！ルーレットもある！
Amazing! There's even a roulette table!
うわあ、めっちゃいじって…
Wow, so cool…
いい、いいよね、このカジノね。
This casino is really nice, isn't it?
そして！きま、きま、きた！
And! It, it's here!
きた！みんながお待ちかねの、スロットーーー！
It's here! Everyone's long-awaited... slot machines!
やったーーー！イェーーーイ！
Yay! Yeah!
いやー、いいよね、スロット打ちてえ！
Man, it's great, I wanna play slots!
そしてこのクソでかソファね！何人掛け？何にするんだっていうねクソでかソファね、これ何にするんだよ本当ね
And this damn huge sofa! What's the point of such a huge sofa? What is it even for, seriously?
やあ、そして！お！HoloXのロゴ！
And! Oh, the HoloX logo!
これもしかすと…これロックスゴ！消して、トリル…するのかな？
Wait, is this... Wow, HoloX! Is it going to vanish and...?
どうだろうね？
I wonder?
ええ、でもめっちゃかっこいいよね！
Eh, but it looks so cool!
カジノの雰囲気も合ってて、いいなって思うよね。
It fits the casino vibe so well, I think it's great.
そして、まあ色々ね、魅力的なセクションがあったんですけど、
And, well, there were various attractive sections,
今回はあちらのテーブルで遊びたいと思いまーす！
but this time we want to play at that table over there!
じょーじょーそっちのテーブルに行こうかな。
Slowly, slowly, let's head to that table.
レッツゴー！およいぎまーす！
Let's go! Swimming over!
およい…ぶくぶくぶくぶく…
Swimming… glub glub glub…
あーーー！当たった！！きたきたきたきた！
Ahhhh! I won!! It's here, it's here, it's here!
じゃあ、見て！これすごくない？
Now, look! Isn't this amazing?
ちゃんとテーブルについて、今回はゲームにチャレンジしていきたいと思います！
Sitting properly at the table, today we're going to challenge a game!
そして今回チャレンジするゲームは！ハイアンドローです！
And the game we're challenging today is! High & Low!
ハイアンドロー、みんな知ってるかな？
Does everyone know High & Low?
ハイアンドローっていうのは、1枚カードをめくって出された数字より大きいか、高いか、低いかで当てていくゲームとなっております。
High & Low is a game where you flip a card and guess whether the next number will be higher or lower than the shown number.
で、トイシ、おい、が…マネーちゃんで見るの殴られそう！ちょっと待って、やめてよ！
And, Toyishi—hey! Looking at Manager-chan makes me feel like I'll get punched! Wait, stop it!
え、じゃあ、え、こーれって、マネちゃんがかっ、坂本が勝ったらチップもらえて、マネちゃんが勝ったら…え、チップ取られるの？
Eh, so, eh, does this mean if Manager-chan—if Sakamata wins, I get chips, and if Manager-chan wins, eh, my chips get taken?
いや、絶対ずっと、ずっと勝つからね！絶対勝つ！やだやだやだ、これしないで、しないで！坂本絶対勝つから！
No, I'll definitely win all the time! I'll definitely win! No, no, no, don't do this, don't! Sakamata will definitely win!
じゃあ、えっと自分のね、カードの数字が相手のカードの数字より大きいと思ったらハイ、小さいと思ったらロー。
So, um, if you think your card's number is higher than your opponent's, it's High; if lower, Low.
で、カードをめくってセングが当たった場合は勝ちで、外れた場合は負けの簡単なルールとなっております。
Then you flip the card, and if your guess is right, you win; if wrong, you lose. Simple rules!
1が一番弱い最弱で、キングが最強！
1 is the weakest, and King is the strongest!
キングが最強だから、キングを手元に引けば勝ってって感じかな？
King is the strongest, so if you draw a King, you win, something like that?
ちょっと…いやー楽しみになってきたと、楽しみ、なんだろな。
Man, I'm getting excited, I wonder how it'll go!
じゃあ行きますか？まあ、坂本の都合に勝てる人いないよね！
Shall we go? Well, nobody can beat Sakamata's convenience!
お、まずはマネちゃんがめくるらしい。
Oh, first Manager-chan is going to flip.
じゃあ、マネちゃんが親として…何、なんだろうなんだろう。うわ、やめて！
So, as the dealer… what could it be? Wow, stop!
あ、4！4か！
Ah, 4! A 4!
え、これるとさ、だいぶ分かりやすいよね。
Eh, this makes it pretty easy to figure out, right?
いやー、ローだ嫌い！ローのジェスチャーしてくるけどロー嫌いでしょう！
Man, Low! No way! You're making a Low gesture, but you hate Low, right?
え、坂本はハイで行きたいと思います！
Eh, Sakamata wants to go with High!
いや、なんでこうかしてんの、絶対こっちの方がいいに決まってるじゃん！
I mean, why would I do that? High is definitely better!
いや、どう考えても4よりさ、ちっちゃい数字なんて出ないから！
I mean, no matter how you think about it, a number smaller than 4 won't come out!
いいですか？めいっぱいくるね！いきます！
Ready? Here it comes! Here we go!
ほい！
Hoy!
やったーー！Jだ！こちこち！
Yay! A Jack! Easy win!
いや、もっともらってきます、これもっともらってきまーす！
Man, taking more, taking more chips!
あれ、マネちゃん弱くね？
Huh, isn't Manager-chan weak?
これさ、坂本全勝しちゃうかな？いや、ちゅうちゅうだよネ！
Could Sakamata win every single time? Yay, easy win!
じゃあ次は坂本が…ちょっとミスしちゃった、ちょっと。ちょっと坂本が次は親で行きたいと思います！
Next, Sakamata—oops, made a little mistake. Next, Sakamata will be the dealer!
2回戦目ね。行くよ？
Round 2. Here we go?
じゃあ坂本どんなカードか、みんな予想して！いくよ？
Now, everyone guess what Sakamata's card is! Ready?
ぱん！7！
Boom! A 7!
あーちょっと、ちょっとどうなるな、どう出てくるか悩ましいところだな。
Ah, man, I wonder how this is gonna go, a bit tricky to guess.
まりちゃんどっちにするのかな？
Mari-chan, which will you choose?
なのだよ、7。え、7って…
It's a 7. Eh, a 7...
どっちの…金返さないで！
Which one... Don't take my money!
待って待って、あ、わかったわかった。
Wait, wait, ah, I get it now.
でもさ、でもさ、あんま変わんないよ？どうすんの？
But you know, it doesn't change much. What should I do?
え、どう？ローで行くの？
Eh, what's this? Should I go Low?
ローだよね？ロー、ロー。別にいっか。
It's Low, right? Low, Low. Whatever.
まあ、そんな大したないし、うん、全然いいか。
Well, it's not a big deal. Yeah, totally fine.
ローで、あ、あ、わかった。
Go Low, ah, okay, I got it.
どうぞどうぞ。まじで？あ、はははは。
Go ahead. Seriously? Ah, hahaha.
ええ！？ええ！？
What?! What?!
これ？坂又狂えの？
This? Sakamata is going crazy?
やだ！ねえ！通さないで！やだねはははは！
No way! Hey! Don't let it pass! No way, hahaha!
ねえ、ねえ！ずる！
Hey, hey! That's cheating!
ずるだよそれ！なんだよ！
That's totally cheating! Come on!
やだ、坂又が勝つ。
No, Sakamata's gonna win.
次、次、次では絶対当てるから。
Next time, next time, I'll definitely get it right.
次まりちゃんの番だから。
It's Mari-chan's turn next.
どうぞ、めくって？何々？
Go ahead, flip it? What is it?
ねえ！チラさないで！
Hey! Don't peek!
チラさないでよ！ハイアンドロー！ハイアンドロー！ねぇ！
Don't peek! High & Low! High & Low! Hey!
うわあ！8か！
Whoa! An 8!
いやいやいや、もう、これは、ね、やっぱね、ちょっと圧倒的に頭がいいのでね、坂又ちゃんは。
No, no, no, well, you know, Sakamata-chan has overwhelmingly superior intellect, after all.
もう、ローかな？ローだよね？
So, Low? It's Low, right?
ローロー。絶対ローだな。
Low, Low. Definitely Low.
でもね、坂又ね、運いいから絶対勝てるはずなんだよね。マジで。
But you know, I'm lucky so I should totally win. Seriously.
あの、運で負けたことあんましないから、ガチで。
Like, I hardly ever lose due to bad luck, for real.
次いきますよ。カードは？
Let's go to the next one. The card is?
はい！
Here!
あ！やったやった！よかったよかった！
Ah! Yay! Thank goodness!
今頭バグってさ。え、ずっと最強だっけ？みたいになってた。
My brain was lagging. I was like, 'Wait, am I always the strongest?'
やったー！ガチガチー！
Yay! Solid victory!
やったやった！え、これまりちゃん？
Yay! Wait, is this Mari-chan's?
え、見て見て！チップの量これすごくない？
Look, look! Isn't this chip stack huge?
え、坂又これ大富豪じゃん！このままちょっと全勝ちしていきたいな。
Sakamata is a millionaire now! I wanna win everything from here.
よし、じゃあ行きますか。
Alright, shall we go?
じゃあ坂又が次親番だね。めくるよ。
Okay, it's my turn as dealer next. I'll flip it.
はい！
Here!
ねえやだ！こ、ここここ、ここでしょ！
No way! H-Here, it's right here!
ん、まりちゃんのターンでも全然いいよ。え、ちょっと、ちょっと、ってさ、ちょっと、ちょっと高いか。ちょ…
Well, Mari-chan's turn is totally fine too. Wait, hold on...
ちょ、やめてやめてやめて！やめてよ！やめてやめて！ローじゃないでしょ！
Wait, was that a bit too high?
やだよやる！ちょっと返して！
Wait, stop, stop, stop! Don't do that! It's not Low!
なんで！えないよー…
I won't let you! Give it back!
やろやろ！絶対坂又が勝つから！
Why! No way...
あ、坂又の勝ちじゃん！
Let's do this! Sakamata's gonna win for sure!
え！？坂又の勝ちじゃん！え？え？ねえ待って！やだー！
Ah, Sakamata won!
え？ねえ！あってるくせに、まきまきのまきじゃん！ねえねえ、坂又強くない？
What?! Sakamata won! Eh? Eh? Wait! No way!
え、これ何回目だっけ？わかんなくなっちゃった。
Eh? Hey! Even though I got it right, it's a loss-loss-loss! Hey, isn't Sakamata strong?
あ、これ坂又か。まあでも見てみてこの、このさ、チップの山絶対坂又が負けるわけないよ、これ。よしよし。
Wait, what time is this? I lost count.
じゃまりちゃんどうぞ。めくりますね。いくよ。はい！
Ah, this is Sakamata's. But look at this chip stack, there's no way I'll lose. Alright, alright.
ええ！？これこっちじゃん！やったー！
Okay, Mari-chan, go ahead. I'll flip it. Here we go. Ha!
え、あ、ローローローロー！ねえやめて！こくしないして！
What?! This is the wrong side! Yay!
坂又のボケはもうちょっと進んだ。お、う、ローローローローロー！はい、メガティ！メガティ！
Eh, ah, Low, Low, Low! Hey, stop! Don't do that!
うわ！どどどど、やったーー！坂又らしきもの！ねえののんだ？よかったよかった！
Sakamata's bumbling continues. Oh, Low, Low, Low! Yes, megative! Megative!
やったー！見て、このチップの山！イエーイ！
Whoa! Yay! Something like Sakamata! Did you drink? Thank goodness!
これ、これどうすんの？勝負？見えますか？
Yay! Look at this mountain of chips! Yay!
よし、今日、坂又が親のターンでしょ、めくりますね。いくよ。
What should I do with this? A match? Can you see?
はい！
Alright, it's my turn as dealer today, I'll flip it. Here we go.
お。お。変えてもらえますか？店員さん、なんかズルされてます、今。
Here!
なんかやってます、この人。ちょっとよくないですか？
Oh. Oh. Can you change this? Clerk-san, I'm getting cheated right now.
え？あ、はい！
This person is doing something shady. Isn't that unfair?
ハイだって！みんな！ハイだってハイだって！
Eh? Ah, High!
じゃあハイで行きましょうハイで！ハイだってハイハイハイイエーイ！
It's High, everyone! High! High!
ハイハイハイ、あ、聞いてます？
Let's go with High! It's High, High, High, yay!
ちょっと、お兄さん？はい、あ、入れた、ほらほらほらほら！
High, High, High, ah, are you listening?
ハイ通って！ハイ通ってよ！ハイ通ってよ！
Excuse me, mister? Yes, ah, it went in, look, look, look!
やったやった！おんって言いながらハイにす…ハイで通ってよ！
High passed! High passed! High passed!
ねえ、おかしいよネ！ハイで通ったじゃん1回！
Yay! Saying 'on' while making it High... High passed!
絶対おかしいよネこのゲーム！
Hey, that's weird! It passed on High once!
This game is totally rigged!
ハイアンドロー！
High and Low!
あ、ちょっ……
Ah, wait...
いや、ずるいよ！ずるい！
No, that's unfair! Unfair!
沙花叉の…沙花叉のジップ引いた！
Sakamata's... It pulled Sakamata's zip!
悲しい……
So sad...
え、じゃ、ラスト？ラスト？
Wait, is this the last one? The last one?
え、シークレットさんどっち？ ちょっと、囲むと、味方して……
Wait, which is the secret card? Everyone, surround it and take my side...
カットラーの2000万枚だって！えっ、スロットの万枚台、2000台！？
20 million coins for Cutter!? Wait, 2,000 slot machines that pay out 10,000!?
やったー！え、これ絶対勝つよみんな！
Yay! Hey, we're definitely gonna win this, everyone!
協力して、協力して！みんな、一緒に勝つよ。そうだ、みんな、一緒に勝つよ。
Cooperative, cooperate! Everyone, let's win together. That's right, everyone, let's win together.
ちょっと応援してね。どっちがいいか考えてね。じゃ、まりちゃんのターン、どうぞ。
Cheer me on a bit. Think about which one is better. Okay, Mari-chan's turn, go ahead.
ラストだよ。いやマジでちょっと緊張する。
It's the last one. No, seriously, I'm getting a bit nervous.
はい。はっ……！
Here. Ha...!
みんな！えっ、みんなこれさ、圧倒的ローだよね？えっ、圧倒的ローでしょ？
Everyone! Wait, isn't this overwhelmingly Low? Wait, isn't it overwhelmingly Low?
みんな、みんなどっちにする？どっちにするこれ？え、ローだよね？え、もうみんなに聞くまでもないか、これ。
Everyone, which one? What do you think? Eh, it's Low, right? Well, do I even need to ask everyone?
どう、どう、どう？みんなどっちがいい？ローだよね？あ、ローだよね？そうだよね？あ、よかったよかったよかった。
How's that? Which one is good? Low, right? Ah, Low, right? That's right, right? Oh, good, good, good.
みんな意見一致してた。よかった。
Everyone's opinions matched. Good.
なんか、なんか、全額かける、え、なんかすごい今「ファイナルアンサー？」みたいな、「全額かけますけど」って言われて。
It's like, bet all-in, wait, it's like someone asked me, "Final answer?" like, "You're betting everything?"
えっ？いやいやいや！全ベッドで、全ベッドでローで行きたいと思います！
Eh? No no no! With all-in, with all-in, I want to go with Low!
いやでもね、これね、全ベッドずらされたの。えっ、いけるからね！いや、マジで、いやマジでほんとに緊張しすぎた。いや、いけますよね？大丈夫。
No but, my all-in bet got moved. Eh, we can do this! No, seriously, I was so damn nervous. No, we can do it, right? It's fine.
はいっ！
There!
あーーっ！うそーっ！ねえ、うそーっ！え、どっちが、ないでしょ！？
Ahhh! No way! Hey, no way! Eh, which one, no way!?
やめて！やめて！やめて！そこまでジャンプ、あ、こんなの！
Stop! Stop! Stop! Jumping that far, ah, like this!
うそでしょ！？どこ、どこ、どこ、どこ？ここ入った？ここ入った？ほらまだ生きてるこの中で！この中で！
No way!? Where, where, where, where? Did it go in here? Did it go in here? Look, it's still alive in here! In here!
うそでしょ！？どこ、どこ、どこ、どこ？ここに入っ……あっ、あーーっ！
No way!? Where, where, where, where? It went in he... Ah, ahhhh!
ねえ！ひどい！ぴっぴってやる！まりちゃんに！ひどい！沙花叉が勝ってたのに！なにこのゲーム！？
Hey! That's awful! I'll pip-pip you! To Mari-chan! So mean! Even though Sakamata was winning! What is this game!?
お水？はい。え？
Water? Here. Eh?
なんで水落とされたの？黙れって！？ねえ！ひどいよー！
Why was the water dropped? "Shut up"!? Hey! That's awful!
えっ、これで終わり？かわいそうなんだけど、ご褒美？全ベッド、全ベッド？生姜焼きえな？
Eh, is this the end? I feel so bad, is this a reward? All bets, all bets? Ginger pork Ena?
これが、ご褒美？キッスの息、キッスの息、ちょっと、ちょっと、唇当て
Is this my reward? Kiss breath, kiss breath, wait, wait, pressing lips
これがご褒美なの？ふざけんな！ふざけんな！ふざけんな！ちけ！
Is this my reward? You've gotta be kidding me! No way! No way! Damn it!
やら、沙花叉の勝っちを、お前のせいで、うわあ！お前がいたから負けたんじゃないの！ひどいよ！あんまりだ！うわあ！
Dammit, Sakamata's win, because of you, uwaah! Didn't I lose because you were here!? That's awful! Too cruel! Uwaah!
うわあああ！なんで負けたの沙花叉！ひどい！ひどいよあんまりだ！
Uwaaaaaah! Why did Sakamata lose!? So awful! So cruel and awful!
誰か助けて！誰が、誰が、えっ、これだけなんですか？え、他に本当に何もないの？
Someone help! Who, who, eh, is this really all? Eh, is there really nothing else?
えっ、あれ？わかりました。
Eh, huh? I see.
こいつ、え、こいついるまんまなのだね。オッケー、はい。あ、じゃあ、ちょっと、負け負けね、負けちゃいましたけど、
This guy, eh, this guy is just staying here. Okay, yes. Ah, well, I lost and lost, but
沙花叉のかっこいいところをね、見てもらいたいなと思うので、ここで、ちょっと、気づいた人もいるんじゃないかな。
I want you to see Sakamata's cool side, so right here, I think some of you might have already noticed.
なんとライブステージが、この部屋にはあるんですね！そこでお、沙花叉、歌わせていただきたいと思います！どうどうどう、いいかな、いいかな？どう？
Surprisingly, there is a live stage in this room! So, I'd like to sing a song there, Sakamata! How's that, is it okay, is it okay? How is it?
こいつしかいないの。ね、いいよいいよ、お前はいい、お前のレスペッサは全然求めてないから。
Only this guy is here. Hey, fine, fine, you're fine, I definitely don't want your respect.
はい、では行きたいと思います！レッツ、ゴー！！
Alright, then I'd like to go! Let's, go!!
はい、ここでお知らせです。6月16日木曜日20時から、沙花叉クロヱの、え、同期のハラクセー、白衣こよりの3Dがお披露目されます。
Right, here is an announcement. Starting at 20:00 on Thursday, June 16th, Sakamata Chloe's, um, fellow gen mate, Hakui Koyori's 3D reveal will take place!
こんくゆー！こんくゆー！白衣こよりだよー！
Konkyuu! Konkyuu! It's Hakui Koyori!
ちょっと、バカにしずらいっしょ。
It's kind of hard to make fun of.
おへそがね、めちゃくちゃエッチなのと、あと実はね、今隠れているんですけど、足もね、素晴らしくエッチでした。
Her belly button is super lewd, and actually, though it's hidden right now, her legs are wonderfully lewd too.
そして尻尾もね、みんなお待たせ女子こお待たせの尻尾もみ
And her tail too, everyone's awaited girl's awaited tail is also...
ということで、3D配信楽しみにしててください！
So please look forward to the 3D stream!
はい、さかまたクロヱのニュースはこちら、
Yes, Sakamata Chloe's news is right here,
どん！
ta-da!
さかまた……クロヱの、なんだっけ？センタージグス……えぇ、もうボロクソなっちゃった！
Sakamata... Chloe's, what was it? Center jigs... Ugh, I completely messed up!
はい、アクリルジオラマスタンド、販売中です！
Yes, the acrylic diorama stand is on sale!
見てみて、これ真似してみれば、どう？こんな可愛いアクリルジオラマスタンドがついております！
Look, look, if you imitate this, how's this cute acrylic diorama stand?
そして、噂になっちゃってる、とか、なってないとか聞きますけど、噂のブレスレット！
And we've heard rumors about it... the rumored bracelet!
そしてチョーカーチャームね、沙花叉のこれとお揃いです！
And the choker charm, it matches Sakamata's!
そして、記念ボイス！こちら全てがセットになっている全部セットでは、特典ボイスと、直筆メッセージ付きポストカードがつきます！
And the anniversary voice! The full set includes a bonus voice and handwritten message postcard!
特典ボイスでは沙花叉が珍しくちょっとだけ照れてたり、
In the bonus voice, Sakamata is unusually a bit shy,
そして直筆メッセージ付きポストカードは汚い字に想いを込めました！
and for the postcard, I put my feelings into my messy handwriting!
マジで読めるかどうかんないけど、ぜひよろしくお願いします！バイバーイ！
I honestly don't know if you can read it, but please look forward to it! Bye-bye!
アップダウンは世の常
Rising and falling is pretty normal in this world,
クズ引いたって動じない
even if I draw a bad hand, I won't let it show.
肝心なのは Strong な Mind
It's very important to have a strong mind,
出し抜いて Survive
outsmart them and survive.
行きつく先は Heaven or hell
Are we heading to heaven or hell?
この世界のルール
This world has only one rule:
たった一つ 勝者こそが正義
the winner is always right.
女は度胸
Being a woman is all about guts.
焦れさせるのアイツは
I'm gonna keep him guessing.
やれること なんだってやる
I'll do anything I have to.
あたしは賭け狂いのクイーン
I'm a compulsive gambling queen.
お見通しそれ You doubt me
I can see right through you, you doubt me.
読み切って レッツ Showdown
Reading all the signs, let's have a showdown.
見透かして あたしのものにする あなたの髪の一本まで全部
I'll see right through you and make you all mine, down to the very last hair on your head.
A million dollars I'd say raise 震えてるわよ 坊や
A million dollars, I'd say raise, I'm simply trembling, my boy.
降ろさちはしないわ
I won't let you drop out.
Uhhhhnn 興奮 たまらないわ スリル
Uhhhn, what an excitement, I can't have enough of this thrill,
誰にも触らせない この Money
I won't let anyone touch this money.
A million dollars I'd say raise さあ Com'on 覚悟キメテ
A million dollars, I'd say raise, so come on and make up your mind.
震え高ぶる My heart 欲しがるようじゃね まだベイビー
Tremble and go wild, my heart, only ever wishing means you're still a baby.
誰にも負けない 感じさせて Love me honey
I won't lose to anyone, so make me feel: love me, honey.
あなた内緒だわ ほら見せてあげる 秘密って甘いの
It's a secret, but I'm gonna reveal all of it to you.
仕掛けて罠に嵌めるわ
Secrets are so sweet, I'll use them in a trap to catch you.
油断誘うのよ 思考を止め たら ジ・エンド
I'll lure your carelessness, if you stop thinking, that would be the end,
何にも知らないような表情で 堕とすわあなたを
with a face that says I don't know a thing, I'll bring you down.
虚勢でしょそれ You doubt me 読み切って レッツ Showdown
You're bluffing, aren't you? You doubt me, reading all the signs, let's have a showdown.
Deal with the devil 見逃さない
Deal with the devil, I won't miss it,
どんな小さなズルだって あたしの目はごまかされないわ
no matter how small the cheat is, you can't fool my eyes.
A million dollars I'd say raise 勝った相手は骨まで
A million dollars, I'd say raise, I love the ones I conquer all the way down to their bones.
愛尽くしてあげる 狙った獲物は逃がさない 唇濡らして頂くわ My babe
I won't lose sight of my prey, I will be wetting my lips before I taste you, my babe.
ダイヤのジャックで手が揃うわ 笑みを殺し待つだけ
With the jack of diamonds, my hand will be complete, I just have to hide my smile and wait.
あたしのポーカーフェイスは It's perfect 一分の隙も見せたりしないわ
My poker face? It's perfect, I will keep it up no matter what.
視線感じてるわ
I can feel your gaze,
お望みは最後まで
until the very end.
見てばっかりいないで
Don't just keep watching me.
あたしとしていかない？
Won't you come with me?
負けるのが怖い？ You're easy game.
Are you afraid to lose? You're easy game.
見透かして あたしのものにする
I'll see right through you and make you mine,
あなたの髪の一本まで全部
down to the very last hair on your head.
あべこべ あたしを乱して震わせるわよ おいおい
A million dollars, I'd say raise...
とことんまで行くわ
We're going all the way.
じわじわ ときめき 本当にたまらないわ
This thrill brings endless excitement.
誰にも触らせない この Money
I won't let anyone touch this money.
あべこべ あたしを乱して さあ Com'on 覚悟きめて
So come on and make up your mind.
はいになるまで打って
Keep hitting until we're high.
欲しがるようじゃね まだベイビー
Only ever wishing means you're still a baby.
誰にも負けない感じさせて Love me honey
So make me feel like no one else can: love me, honey.
はあ、みんみん、どうだった？
Whew, everyone, how was it?
結構頑張ってみたんだけど、どうどうどうどう？
I tried really hard, how was it?
いや、かなりね、練習もたくさん頑張って、練習も本当にたくさん頑張って来たので
Man, I practiced really, really hard...
うまく歌えてたらいいなって思います。どうだった？ よかった？
So I hope I sang it well. How was it? Was it good?
よかった！ あ、よかった！ マジでよかった！ イェーイ！
It was good! Ah, it was good! Seriously good! Yay!
すごい、ありがとうございます！ イェーイ！
Thank you so much! Yay!
ではでは、ライブはまだまだ続きます。今度は水族館で準備ができてみたいだから
Now then, the live continues. Next is the aquarium where preparations seem ready.
移動しちゃうよ！ いかな？ いけ？
We're moving there! Shall we go? Let's go!
レッツゴー！ すいすいすいすい！
Let's go! Swim, swim, swim, swim!
やっぱ水だな、やっぱ。
Water is the best, after all.
えっ？ 誰？ こいつ呼んだの？ いらない。
Huh? Who? Who called this guy? I don't need it.
お前帰れって。
Go home.
お前帰って、鮭男の旦那の代わりで...
Go home and replace Mr. Salmon...
やっぱ帰れや！
Go home already!
お前！
Hey you!
いらない！
I don't need you!
くそ、お前... くそっ！
Damn you... Damn it!
はい、到着しました！ 水族館。
Okay, we've arrived! At the aquarium.
実はね、さっき言ってなかったんだけど、すごい仕掛けを用意してもらったんです。
Actually, I didn't say it earlier, but they prepared an amazing gimmick.
じゃあーん！ 天井... どうぞ！
Ta-da! The ceiling... go ahead!
わあ、すごい！ 天井が閉じました！
Wow, amazing! The ceiling closed!
みんなこれで課金も怖くないねって。
Everyone won't be scared of gacha spending with this.
全然怖くない。天井天井じゃないですけど。
Not scary at all. Not a gacha pity ceiling though.
はい！ めっちゃいいでしょ。坂本の仮面の模様になってるんですよ。
Right! Isn't it great? It's patterned after Sakamata's mask.
めちゃくちゃいいよね。そして、まだあるんですよ。行くよ！
It's super nice. And there's more. Here we go!
せーの、じゃーん！
Ready, set, ta-da!
すごーい！ 見て見て！
Amazing! Look, look!
水族館の中にみんな入り込んじゃった！ めちゃくちゃいいよね。
Everyone got inside the aquarium! Isn't it super nice?
このセットにめちゃくちゃ合う曲を選んで来ました。みんな聞いてくれるかな？
I chose a song that fits this set perfectly. I wonder if everyone will listen?
すごい？ あ！ よかったよかった！ じゃあみんな期待してな。いくよ！ 歌います、「海の幽霊」。
Amazing? Ah, good, good! Then everyone look forward to it. Here we go! I'll sing "Umi no Yuurei".
開け放たれた この部屋には 誰もいない
The door is open, no one's inside.
潮風の匂い 染み付いた椅子がひとつ
Just a chair that smells of the ocean breeze.
あなたが迷わないように 開けておくよ
I'll keep it open so you won't get lost.
軋む戸を叩いて
Pushing open the creaking door.
あなたが迷わないように あけておくよ
So you won't get lost, I'll leave it open.
軋む戸を叩いて
Knocking on the creaking door,
何から話せばいいのか わからないから
Wondering what to talk about first,
ああ
Ah...
星が降る夜に あなたにあえた
I met you on a night when stars were falling.
あの夜を忘れはしない
I will never forget that night.
大切なことは 言葉にならない
The most important things cannot be put into words.
夏の日に起きたすべて
Everything that happened on that summer day,
思いがけず 光るのは 海の幽霊
shining unexpectedly is the ghost of the sea.
躙る夏の日に 梢が
In the sweltering summer evening, treetops
舟を見送る
see off the ships.
いくつかの歌を 囁く 花を散らして
Whispering a few songs and scattering flowers,
あなたがどこかで笑う 声が聞こえる
I can hear your voice laughing somewhere,
熱い頬の手ざわり
the touch of your warm cheeks.
ねじれた道を進んだら その瞼が開く
If you go down the twisted road, those eyelids open.
離れ離れでもときめくほど 叫ぼう 今は幸せと
Even apart, let's shout out that we're happy now.
離れ離れでも ときめくもの 叫ぼう
Even apart, whatever makes my heart flutter, let's shout it out,
今は幸せと
that we are happy now.
大切なことは 言葉にならない
The most important things cannot be put into words,
跳ねる光に溶かして 星が降る夜に
dissolving into splashing light, on a night when stars fall
あなたにあえた
I was able to meet you.
あのときを忘れはしない
I will never forget that time.
大切なことは 言葉にならない
The most important things cannot be put into words,
夏の日に起きたすべて
everything that happened on that summer day.
思いがけず 光るのは 海の幽霊
Shining unexpectedly is the ghost of the sea.
風薫る砂浜で また会いましょう
On the sandy beach scented with wind, let's meet again.
また会いましょう
Let's meet again.
はあ、めっちゃ、めっちゃ緊張しちゃった！ちょっと声震えちゃってたら、ごめんなさい。
Phew, I was so, so nervous! I'm sorry if my voice was shaking.
でもめっちゃ練習したのどうだった？どうだった？どうだった？いい感じだったね、ね、ね、ね！よかった？
But how was it since I practiced so much? How was it? Was it good? Right, right! Was it nice?
沙花叉がね、海の生物なので、海の幽霊、ちょっと選んでみました。
Since Sakamata is a sea creature, I chose 'Ghost of the Sea'.
めちゃくちゃね、このステージも綺麗なステージなので、合ってたんじゃないかなって思います！どうだった、どうだった？よかった？あ、よかったー！
It's such a gorgeous stage too, so I think it fit really well! How was it? Was it good? Ah, yay!
ではでは、まだまだね、3Dの姿お見せしたかったんですが、次が最後の曲になります。
Well then, I wanted to show you my 3D form a bit more, but the next song will be the last one.
実もね、配信後に今は秘密だよってなってたんだけど、キミらの歌ってみたがプレミア公開で上がりますので、そちらの方も楽しみに待ってててください。9時半から上がります！よろしくお願いします！
Actually, after the stream—it was a secret until now—your cover song will premiere, so please look forward to that too. It goes live at 9:30! Thanks for watching!
じゃあ、次の曲ラストリーズが、行きたいと思います。それでは聞いてください、あなたがいることで。
Well then, for the next and final song, let's go. Please listen to 'Anata ga Iru Koto de'.
どんな言葉で
With what words
今あなたに伝えられるだろう
can I convey it to you now?
不器用な僕だけど
Though I'm clumsy,
ちゃんとあなたに届くように
so that it properly reaches you.
明日が見えなくなって
When tomorrow becomes invisible
信じる事が怖くなって
and believing becomes scary,
過去を悔やんでは責めたりもしたけれど
I regretted and blamed the past, but...
僕を愛し続けてくれた人
the person who kept on loving me.
もしも明日世界が終わっても
Even if the world were to end tomorrow,
会えない日々が続いたとしても
and days without meeting continue,
僕はずっとあなたを想うよ
I will always think of you.
あの日僕にくれたあなたの笑顔が
That smile you gave me that day
生きる力と勇気をくれたんだ
gave me the strength and courage to live.
星が見えない 孤独な夜でも
Even on lonely nights when stars cannot be seen,
あなたがいる ただそれだけで
just having you there alone
強く なれる
makes me strong.
目が合えば笑って
When our eyes meet, we smile;
一緒にいれば楽しくて
it's fun when we're together.
共に過ごした毎日々は
Every day we spent together
かけがえのないものだった
was something irreplaceable.
向かい風が冷たくて
The headwind was cold,
忘れてしまいそうになるけど
and I almost forgot it, but...
通り過ぎてきた何気ない日々の中に
in the casual days that passed by,
僕らの幸せは確かにあった
our happiness was definitely there.
もしも眠れない夜の中で
Even if in a sleepless night
一人静かに泣いているのなら
you are quietly crying alone,
あなたが僕を信じてくれたように
just as you believed in me,
今度は僕がその手を強く握るから
I will hold your hand tightly this time.
傷つくことから逃げていた
I had been running away from getting hurt,
この心動かすのは
and what moves this heart
弱さを見せないあなたが初めて見せた涙
are the tears you showed for the first time.
いつか僕に話してくれた
You talked to me sometime...
あなたが描いた未来の中に
In the future you once drew for me,
僕ら一緒にいられるように
so we can be together.
あなたがいることで どんな明日も
Because you are here, no matter what tomorrow brings,
歩いていける 光になるから
it will become a light I can walk towards.
星が見えない 孤独な夜でも
Even on lonely nights when stars cannot be seen,
信じられる 僕らまたここで
I can believe we can smile here again.
笑える日を
The day we can smile.
飼育員さんへ
To my zookeepers,
沙花叉クロヱを見つけてくれて応援してくれてありがとう！
Thank you for finding and supporting Sakamata Chloe!
みんなの声が沙花叉の宝物だよ。
Everyone's voices are Sakamata's treasure.
これからも沢山の思い出をつくっていこうね！大好きだよ
Let's make many more memories together! I love you!
はい、ということで
Yes, so...
今日の3Dお披露目ライブ みんな来てくれてありがとうございました！
Thank you all for coming to today's 3D debut live stream!
たくさん頑張ったし みんながね、こうやって応援してくれて
I worked really hard, and seeing everyone cheering me on like this...
沙花叉も3Dができたと思いますので
...I feel like I was able to become 3D too.
これからもね ライブやいろんな目標に向かって
From now on too, toward live shows and various goals,
頑張っていきたいと思います！
I want to keep doing my best!
本当にみんな いつも応援ありがとう！
Thank you all so much for always supporting me!
ありがとう！じゃあね！
Thank you! See you!
おい！
Hey!
ちょ、ちょっとちょっと！ちょっとちょっと！
W-Wait, wait! Hold on!
あ、かわいい沙花叉ちゃんいいけど、あの、ええーっ！？
Ah, cute Sakamata-chan is fine, but um, whaaat!?
沙花叉クロヱ 3Dお披露目
[Sakamata Chloe 3D Debut]